# **Chris Wolff**

linkedin.com/in/thewolff • me@wolffisthe.best • 407.496.3732

### **PROFILE**

Award-winning front-end developer with 13 years of experience creating, optimizing, and rapidly deploying outstanding websites. Accomplished in tailoring experiences and approaches to distinct verticals, and building systematic approaches to development to accelerate delivery. Proficient in JavaScript, React with experience with Redux client stores, Less, and Sass.

#### **SKILLS**

- CSS (Less, Sass/SCSS BEM)
- HTML
- Javascript (React, NextJS, Redux)
- Python (Django)

- UX/UI development and optimization
- Responsive web design
- Website accessibility and page speed
- Web standards and guidelines

- A/B testing
- Agile methodology and ceremonies
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Usability and user experience

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Software Engineer, **Apartment Therapy Media** (2018-2023)

Partnered with design and editorial stakeholders to build Apartment Therapy's modern publishing infrastructure powered by Wordpress, replacing AT Media's legacy CMS. The newly relaunched Apartment Therapy and Kitchn sites powered via GraphQL and NextJS server side rendering and caching allowed for evergreen updates to legacy content, which helped rank both sites in the top 5 of Comscore in their categories between 2020 and 2022. Served as frontend lead on the SEO product team, working on initiatives to highlight archival content with an emphasis on page performance and benchmarking.

# Senior Frontend Engineer, **Noun Project** (2013-2018)

Managed all client-side development of Noun Project's modern infrastructure, which allowed for monthly subscriptions and API access for Noun Project members securing monthly recurring revenue for the Noun Project site. As the team grew, we moved Noun Project's component library to React + Redux, which allowed for faster page loading and a better user experience for designers and Noun Project users. Led all client-side development of the Saas marketplace, as well as special projects, which included Adobe's web-powered icon plugin used directly in Adobe products.

## Web developer, **Obama for America** (2011-2012)

As the second developer on Digital Development for barackobama.com, I built a boilerplated design system that enabled the team to rapidly take microsites, infographics, and donation pages from concept to completion within hours, driving more than \$600 million in fundraising. This supported a breakneck pace of development and deployment across critical workstreams, including rapid response communications, fundraising, and voter registration and messaging, as the team quintupled in size over 15 months.

#### **AWARDS**

- BarackObama.com (Webby Awards Winner, 2012 Breakout of the Year)
- ApartmentTherapy.com (Webby Awards Honoree, 2021 Websites and Mobile Sites Lifestyle)
- TheKitchn.com (Webby Awards Honoree, 2021 Social Food & Drink)

# **EDUCATION**

B.A. in Digital Media Technology (Minor in Web Development), Columbia College Chicago